Finding aid for the Harry French Blaney papers, 1919-1970 LSC.1682
UCLA Library Special Collections
Harry French Blaney papers
1919-1970
UCLA Library Special Collections
Blaney, Harry French
LSC.1682
31 Linear Feet (52 boxes, 5 cartons, and 4 oversize boxes)
Harry French Blaney (1892-1976) worked for the U.S. Department of Agriculture (1917-62), was a research associate in the Department of Irrigation Research and Soil Science at UCLA (1962-65), and served in the Department of Engineering and Water Resource Center (1965-73). He was also the author of many publications on consumptive use of water, irrigation, evaporation, and water supply. The collection consists of materials documenting Blaneys career as an irrigation engineer and researcher.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Water Resources Center Archives, UCLA, transfer, 1991.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 997093843606533
Biography
Blaney was born in Los Angeles, California, July 19, 1892; BS, civil engineering, UC Berkeley, 1915; spent most of career working for U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA), 1917-62; research associate, Department of Irrigation Research and Soil Science, UCLA, 1962-65; served in Department of Engineering and Water Resource Center, 1965-73; author of many publications on consumptive use of water, irrigation, evaporation, and water supply; died in 1976.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of materials documenting Blaneys career as an irrigation engineer and researcher. Includes reports, writings, research notes, photographs, and correspondence related to moisture loss, waste water, irrigation, soil, and evapotranspiration. Also includes correspondence and proceedings of the American Society of Civil Engineers (ASCE).
Related Material
Harry F. Blaney: water conservation engineer [oral history transcript] / Harry French Blaney, interviewee. UCLA Oral History Department interview, 1963. Available at UCLA Library Special Collections.
Water-supply engineering -- Research.; Irrigation engineers -- California -- Archives.; University of California, Los Angeles--Faculty -- Archives; American Society of Civil Engineers.; Blaney, Harry French, 1892-1976--Archives.
- Reports and writings., 1940s-1950s (Box 1)
- Reports and writings., 1940s (Box 2)
- Correspondence. (Box 3)
- Reports, including typed with photos., 1930s [?] (Box 4)
- Reports and writings., 1930s-1950s (Box 5)
- Moisture loss in soils ... (Box 6)
- Equipment. (Box 7)
- Irrigation. (Box 8)
- Correspondence, ASCE [American Society of Civil Engineers] material. (Box 9)
- ASCE material. (Box 10)
- ASCE material, drainage, Pecos River, agriculture. (Box 11)
- Consumptive use of water, ASCE material. (Box 12)
- ASCE material, personal files. (Box 13)
- Personal files, consumptive use of water. (Box 14)
- Consumptive use of water, drainage, annual report., 1950 (Box 15)
  Scope and Contents note
  Also, reprints, research.
- Reprints, research notes, data. (Box 16, Box 17)
- Photographs. (Box 18)
- Photographs and notebook. (Box 19)
- Notebooks. (Box 20)
- ICID Bulletin, Pecos river, ASCE convention. (Box 21)
- Files. (Box 22)
- Files, Pecos River, Rio Grande. (Box 23)
- Reports. (Box 24)
- Reports and reprints. (Box 25)
- Soil, waste water. (Box 26)
- Waste water, Imperial Valley water reclamation, Journal of the Irrigation and Drainage Division ASCE. (Box 27)
- Waste water, articles by Blaney, reprints, Kern County. (Box 28)
- Water use, reprints, drainage. (Box 29)
- Arizona California litigation, upper Gila River investigations, irrigation. (Box 30)
- Around the world tour., 1959 (Box 31)
- Conservation conferences and reports., 1940-1958 (Box 31)
- Notes on conference of division of irrigation engineering and water conservation - SCS., 1952 (Box 32)
  Also, water conservation, diary 1923.
- Arizona, New Mexico, California vs. Arizona, irrigation, evaporation, Colorado river, New Zealand and Australia. (Box 33)
- Reports, articles, water use. (Box 34)
- Evapotranspiration, ground water replenishment, reports - West Coast Basin, irrigation, consumptive water use. (Box 35)
- Evapotranspiration, ASCE, ASAE, writings of H.B. Blaney by Cullen and Willard. (Box 36)
- Photos, card files. (Box 37)
- Clippings file, water analysis. (Box 38)
- Gypsum in agriculture, improvement of irrigation systems. (Box 39)
- Scrapbook, Piedmont province., 1934 (Box 40)
- Brant sealing gasket technical manual, ground water. (Box 41)
- Engineering digest, botany. (Box 42)
- Irrigation and water levels. (Box 43)
- Proceedings of ASCE, Journal of Irrigation and Drainage Division ASCE. (Box 44)
- Journal of Irrigation and Drainage Division ASCE, and irrigation in Mexico. (Box 45)
- Annual reports, Division of irrigation, State Water Rights Board., 1947-1948 (Box 46)
- Association of Western State Engineers., 1953 (Box 47)
- Salinity, evapotranspiration, articles. (Box 48)
- Annual report, evaporation., 1952 (Box 49)
- Elementary school material, corrosion, ASAE papers. (Box 50)
- Papers by various authors, Western irrigation practices book, soil conservation. (Box 51)
- Tulare - Bakersfield area, annual reports., 1952 (Box 52)
  Also, Santa Barbara data.
- Articles, irrigation, engineering and maintenance. (Box 53)
- Soil conservation service, USDA. (Box 54)
- Coachella Valley, AGU discussion papers. (Box 55)
- Water quality and consumption, Texas. (Box 56)
- Ground water recharge conference, National Reclamation Association. (Box 57)
- National Reclamation Association, National Water Research Symposium., 1961 (Box 58)
- Los Angeles Chamber of Commerce special reports, articles. (Box 59)
- ASCE Ground Water Committee, ASCE publications Committee. (Box 60)
- Evapotranspiration. (Box 61)